Eric Siegel Los Angeles, CA

ericsiegel448@gmail.com | 310-909-4688

Objective

Experienced Conversion Rate Optimization Strategist and A/B testing developer with 5 years experience in UX/UI strategy, statistical analyses, and web development. I am seeking full time opportunities in a conversion rate optimization, solution's architect, or product manager roles.

Achievements

- Contributed to a mobile application's design that won 1st place in a Google competition for funding in 2019
- Increased user traffic for Logos News Startup to 1000 new monthly users
- Co-founded and managed a 10 member startup, including UI/UX designers, marketers, and web developers

Professional Experience

Spinutech, Conversion Rate Optimization Team, Testing and Optimization Developer 2021 - Present

- Manage Spinutech's AB testing protocol and test development from test ideation to test winner implementation
- Developed a track record of a 50% win rate with A/B tests deployed, with conversion rate lifts averaging around +20% for KPIs
- Consult a variety of clientele, from small businesses to multi-billion dollar corporations, on conversion rate optimization strategy and UX/UI strategy

Siegel UX Consultancy, Principal Consultant

2018 - Present

Below is a sample of clients whom I have worked with as a UX designer and UX researcher:

Logos

- Conducted user interviews for the homepage and article pages to reader engagement
- Redesigned homepage and main feed, increasing reader's positive feedback by 50%.
- Incorporated hyperlinking features that improved the number of writers adding credible sources to their articles by 28%.

Bruinshack

- Manages concept to launch of website helping college students
- Lead a team of 5 UX/UI designers and marketers
- Projected to have 50+ new weekly users in the next couple of months

Skills

- Software: Adobe XD, Figma, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Google Optimize, JIRA, Optimizley, Tableau. Sketch
- Web Development/Programming Languages: CSS, HTML, Javascript, JQuery, Python, R, SQL

Education

University of California, Los Angeles

2016-2020

Bachelor of Science (BS) in Minor in Statistics with a Specialization in Computation, College Honors